[
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Circe",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise mage.",
            "job": "I teach of the axiom!",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "AXIO",
            "keyword2": "PART",
            "answer1": "The whole of the axiom is greater than all its parts!",
            "answer2": "The measure of unending love, the limitless courage needed to face all obstacles,the truth which encompasses all things!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Charm",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A fair sorceress.",
            "job": "I ponder the key to the axiom.",
            "heal": "Well enough.",
            "keyword1": "KEY ",
            "keyword2": "AXIO",
            "answer1": "To the axiom.",
            "answer2": "The 1 pure axiom encompasses all things.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye what they are?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "The truths of the universe, the love of the heart, and the courage of the soul!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shaman",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall mage.",
            "job": "I study the 'one' thing that is the secret to the codex!",
            "heal": "Quite well.",
            "keyword1": "STUD",
            "keyword2": "CODE",
            "answer1": "I study of the codex!",
            "answer2": "The one pure axiom is more endless than the changing tides, more eternal than day and night!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Spellbind",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A slender mage.",
            "job": "I know of the codex.",
            "heal": "Well indeed.",
            "keyword1": "CODE",
            "keyword2": "COMB",
            "answer1": "One must know the combination of the three principles of virtue!",
            "answer2": "The combination of the three principles of virtue equals the measure of time and space!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Brother Zair",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An old druid.",
            "job": "I sit and watch the river.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "RIVE",
            "keyword2": "WORD",
            "answer1": "It flows endlessly.",
            "answer2": "The kings of the castles which represent the three principles of virtue each know but one syllable of the word of passage!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Agree?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Indeed."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 26,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Rabindranath tagore",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise man.",
            "job": "I speak of love.",
            "heal": "I am old but strong!",
            "keyword1": "LOVE",
            "keyword2": "HEAR",
            "answer1": "In love, all life's contradictions dissolve and disappear.",
            "answer2": "Carry love within it!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek to carry love in thy heart?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou art a good soul.",
            "noanswer": "Thou art a fool."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 138,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Blissful",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A majestic seahorse!",
            "job": "I know much of the codex!",
            "heal": "I am doing well.",
            "keyword1": "CODE",
            "keyword2": "ABYS",
            "answer1": "The shrine ankh knows how to enter the chamber of the codex!",
            "answer2": "Meditate at the shrines of honesty, compassion and valor for 3 cycles to know how to enter!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Draconian",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An old druid.",
            "job": "I teach the relation.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "RELA",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "There are eight possible combinations of truth, love and courage. Each of the eight virtues is one of those combinations!",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "Knew ye this?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good!",
            "noanswer": "Learn the towns and castles!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 224,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Merlin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mystical wizard.",
            "job": "I use magic.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "STON",
            "keyword2": "GATE",
            "answer1": "The black stone is caught in a moon gate!",
            "answer2": "Stand where the gate of both moons dark shall appear. Search when the moons go dark!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou study magic?",
            "yesanswer": "Best of luck with thy studies!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Linda",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A singer.",
            "job": "I sing of the children.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "CHIL",
            "keyword2": "WORL",
            "answer1": "All round the world, little children being born to the world.",
            "answer2": "Got to give them all we can 'til the quest is won, then will the work be done!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou help?",
            "yesanswer": "Teach them songs of joy!",
            "noanswer": "Hmm."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 85,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Paul",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A strangely familiar bard.",
            "job": "I play of love.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "LOVE",
            "keyword2": "PROB",
            "answer1": "I light a candle to our love, in love our problems disappear.",
            "answer2": "But all in all we soon discover that one and one is all we long to hear!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou listen?",
            "yesanswer": "About love.",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 61,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 1,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "the ankh",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A shining ankh!",
            "job": "I resonate with thoughts.",
            "heal": "Bright.",
            "keyword1": "CODE",
            "keyword2": "CHAM",
            "answer1": "To enter the codex chamber.",
            "answer2": "One must be 8 parts avatar, have the key of 3 parts, the word of passage and know the pure axiom!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek help?",
            "yesanswer": "What are thy thoughts?",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 224,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Mentorian",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall wizard.",
            "job": "I study the magical arts.",
            "heal": "Well indeed.",
            "keyword1": "ARTS",
            "keyword2": "GATE",
            "answer1": "There is truth in magic!",
            "answer2": "Since thou dost bear the ankh I shall tell thee. A gate spell requires ash, pearl, and mandrake root!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou disagree?",
            "yesanswer": "Well then, begone!",
            "noanswer": "Good."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sloven",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An old hermit.",
            "job": "I am a recluse.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "RECL",
            "keyword2": "STON",
            "answer1": "I have withdrawn from society.",
            "answer2": "Only the ghost of Isaac who haunts the inn at Skara Brae can tell thee.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou seen him?",
            "yesanswer": "Ask him!",
            "noanswer": "Stay at the inn until he shows himself!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Frontis",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small druid.",
            "job": "Welcome to Cove, the hidden city of wisdom.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "WISD",
            "keyword2": "PEAC",
            "answer1": "Herein is found much wisdom and peace.",
            "answer2": "Find peace in our shrine.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou well?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good.",
            "noanswer": "Visit our healers, I am sure they can help thee!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 90,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Allen",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small boy.",
            "job": "I know how to enter the abyss!",
            "heal": "I am fine.",
            "keyword1": "ABYS",
            "keyword2": "SHIP",
            "answer1": "The abyss may only be approached by ship!",
            "answer2": "The ship must have a magically strengthened hull!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou such a vessel?",
            "yesanswer": "Ask Blissful of the abyss.",
            "noanswer": "Ask Blissful of the abyss."
        }
    }
]